Certainly, Mr. Chairman. Uh again, David
Hopinson, deputy city attorney.
Um the proposed ordinance just creates
uh some regulation for private displays
on public property. Uh it effectively
just prohibits uh that a provides that
no person would erect a public display
on uh public property of the city of
Cheyenne uh except as otherwise
expressly permitted by law or expressly
authorized by the city and it provides
some penalties. Um and really I think
just kind of clarifies or provides a
method for
uh the various city departments to know
what to do in this type of situation. Um
there is a proposed substitute that that
simply amends subsection A in 87202
uh by adding language to include any
public right of way uh and removing uh
the language about advertising. So I'd
be happy to answer any questions or or
get more into kind of the purpose or how
it might work.
>> Any questions from the committee for
staff?
Dr. Dr. Renie, any questions?
>> Uh, no, Mr. Chairman. I was just trying
to I presume that the the two amendments
will be discussed. Dr. Aldrich will
present those.
>> She's shaking her her head. Yes. Thank
you.
>> Okay. Thank you, Mr. President.
>> All right. Well, thank you, David.
Please hang around a little bit. We'll
open this up to the public. Would anyone
like to uh address the committee on
this? Any
discussion?
Any discussion online? Okay, we don't
have any. Could we have a motion,
please?
>> I would move to approve.
>> Second.
>> We have a motion by Dr. Aldridge, second
by uh Councilman Lebourne.
>> I would move to approve by substitution
dated
uh February 13th.
>> Do we have a second?
>> Second.
>> All right. Could we have a report on the
uh substitute, please? Well, thank you,
um,
Chairman Secret. I forgot what I was
going to call you. Um, I appreciate the
council's, um, patience with this. Um, I
was out of town at our last council
meeting and I was under I thought that,
um, this was coming forward to you guys
last Monday night. Um, but Mr. Hopkinson
had been sick and we didn't communicate.
So that's why you're seeing the
substitute tonight or today rather than
last Monday night. Um this substitute um
which he uh prepared for us after our
last um conversation about this uh was
to uh add the public rightway. That was
um a concern and was also to um remove
advertising from this um ordinance as we
already have ordinances that cover
advertising. So, um, just to give those
that are watching or here in the
chambers a a background on this, we have
a variety of memorials around our
community that have been on display for
varying lengths of time. The one that is
in Ward 3 that I've had constituents
contact me about is on Nation Way. And
so, um, while Mr. Hopinson and I um
started working on this back in I think
November. Part of the um delay has been
getting a hold of that family and having
the conversation with them about that
memorial. Um this is a really sensitive
subject and I wanted to be um in touch
with them before they just saw this come
into the um on the council agenda.
Um that young woman uh was killed it'll
be five years in March by a drunk driver
and while she was walking across Nation
Way and we've had some motorcycle
accidents in Ward 3 as well. Uh one that
is memorialized by a helmet on Lincoln
Way by the old Sher's restaurant and
that is on uh the private property of
the um
the people that own that shopping area.
There's one on uh College Drive that was
a bicyclist that was killed. Um one of
my former students in fact that um that
is State Highway and so that's under a
different jurisdiction. Um we had two
motorcyclists who were killed at the
corner of Lincoln Way and East Lincoln
East Lincoln Way and Nation Way. And um
because th those were on private
property, there was a varying amount of
time that those could be um erected for
um before the repairs needed to be done
to the building. And then we had a young
man that was killed on Link Lincoln Way
where he flipped his car into the
McDonald's parking lot and that memorial
was up for um about 5 days. So this
would um basically
um put some limitations around that. Um
obviously if someone has a an individual
that has died in a traffic accident,
they want to memorialize them. Um
definitely understand that, but um this
would limit that memorial. they would be
notified with a 7-day notice. Um, and
then that would be removed. Part of the
problem becomes when they've been up for
four or five years, it becomes a
problem, not a problem, but more of a
challenge for our staff to be able to
mow around and to be able to maintain um
that area. Um, and the other part of
that is that, um, there are signs that
are available through the Wyoming
Department of Transportation for free to
a family who would like to memorialize a
loved one who's been killed in a traffic
accident. Um, but those letters have to
be written by the family. It can't be
written by um, another entity. So, I've
provided that family on Nationway with
that information. Um, those signs are
displayed by the Wyoming Highway
Department for 10 years. And then if the
family would like to have that renewed,
that memorial renewed, it's another $50
if they're if they need to replace a
sign due to weather or damage. So, um I
just I think it's important that people
know that this has not been done uh
without a lot of forethought and a lot
of contact with the individuals that are
involved um in that memorial situation.
So, that's a substitute and the
background on why we have a substitute.
Thanks.
>> Thank you, Dr. Aldrich. Any questions
from the committee for Dr.
Councilman Lewin.
>> Thank you, Mr. Chairman. Um, so
to the sponsor,
I believe you mentioned uh notification
by city staff uh as to the the period of
time, the seven days, how do they know
who to notify?
So the way the ordinance can I I'm sorry
you grade through. The way the ordinance
reads is that there would be a notice of
a request to remove the display placed
at the display. Um and then after that
um time period the display would would
be deemed abandoned property and the
city would remove the display not later
than 30 days after providing the written
notice. And to continue, um, I'm
familiar with the Y dot
signs. Um, so would they be providing
them
for people in the city and is
appropriate for the city to be
displaying them?
>> What, Dr. Aldrich,
>> I believe, and I don't know if
Councilman or White is I believe is on
the call. Nope, I don't see him. He's
not on the call this morning. Um, but he
did provide me with that information
which I then provided to the family and
they did say that the sheriff's office
or the police department had provided
them that information when their loved
one was um killed at on Nation Way.
>> Thank you. Well, I have some comments,
Mr. Chairman.
>> Council Labor.
>> Um,
we handle a lot of sensitive matters
here, but this is a very unique and
important one. I really
uh initially thought that this was not
something we should be involved in, but
I did go out to that uh site on Nation
Way and obviously it's more of a
permanent memorial in absolutely the
wrong place.
um that is not somewhere where uh in the
middle of a four-lane
road with a median um at I guess it's
near the crossing of Hot Springs, but
it's just a dangerous place for anyone
to be there. I didn't wasn't there in
the evening, but it looked to me like
they had solar lights uh which might be
proved distracting. But what really
bothered me was that there was another
memorial not far away.
And I think that that's a consideration
here. So
um and obviously there are many many
ways for people to recognize and
memorial their loved ones including
things that we participate in like a
tree or something like that. So I
believe that I'm in support of this, but
I'm also uh
curious about there's another aspect of
all this that I think people take into
consideration, which is uh they wanted
noted that this is a dangerous place.
And certainly uh those of us that have
been around a while know how dangerous
Nation Way can be. It just really is a
long street with a couple of cross
streets, not much. The greenway there to
the south, which didn't used to be
there, and then the neighborhood there
to the north. So, um perhaps we'll see
as we continue here um whether
um how it goes. I think that when I'm
out on the highway and I see those red Y
dot signs,
they also kind of tell me to be careful.
Um that is uh that there possibly
there's something there that is
dangerous. But um overall I I approve of
this and uh believe that it it uh
it giving the opportunity for people to
do that non-permanent placement there.
uh I can understand that and so then
they can be informed that uh it'll be
removed and generally you're talking
flowers and uh some pictures maybe but
um
tough subject but I believe that this is
a bit is a good approach. Thank you.
Thank you. Further questions for the
sponsor of the amendment
>> hearing none.
>> Mr. Mr. Chairman
>> Dr. there any
>> we're on the amendment. Correct.
>> Correct.
>> All right. I'll keep my comments related
to that for now. Um, so the amendment if
because I didn't get it written down
when when our attorney was going through
it, but so it's on 8.72.020A.
We are adding after public property city
rideway on line one and line two we're
deleting advertising. Is that correct?
>> That's correct.
>> All right. Thank you, M. Thank you, Mr.
Chairman.
>> Sure. With that, uh, we'll take public
comment on the substitute. Any public
comment on the substitute?
Public comment. Anyone online? No one
online. Okay, we'll bring it back to the
to the body. Any further discussion on
the uh proposed amendment or substitute?
All right, we'll vote on the substitute.
All those in favor signify by saying I.
>> I.
>> Those opposed.
The substitute is approved. We're back
on the main motion. Further further
discussion from the uh committee
discussion.
>> Mr. Chairman,
>> Dr. Renie.
>> Um, thank you. I think I mean it's been
noted I haven't been in favor of this
from the start. It's been noted that the
display in question on Nationway has
been there for five years. We've not, to
my knowledge, we've not received a
complaint from
um whether it be CRA or public works
that mows that. We've not received a
complaint from the police department
saying that they deem it a hazard or
consider it a hazard. So, um I I guess
at this point I really don't have an
issue with with families putting up
displays like this. We seem to have been
dealing just fine with with the one in
question, the others around town. So I
will be a no vote.
>> Thank you. Further discussion.
>> Yes, sir.
>> Dr. Aldrich.
>> Um Chairman Crave, um I believe that u
Mr. Fountain is in the audience today
and I don't see anybody else from public
works, but um I believe this is a
conversation that I actually have had
with um our city staff and about the
upkeep and maintenance and their
concerns about uh damaging everything
from stuffed animals to um plant, you
know, solar gardening picks to um
objects that are left there. So, um,
they they have had that conversation and
I would encourage my colleague from W 2
to reach out and visit with those
individuals as well.
>> Dr.
>> I will contact them, but to me, the fact
that that they're not present to
contribute to the discussion tells me
that it's not a burning issue for them
either.
>> Further discussion from the committee.
Discussion hearing. None. All those in
favor signify by saying I.
>> I.
>> Those opposed.
>> No.
>> The recommendation for Monday night will
be to approve as amended. Next item,
please. Number 13, Ordinance, second
reading, amending the official zoning
map of the city of Cheyenne, changing
the zoning classification for certain
land located north of Prairie Avenue,
east of Powderhouse Road, west of
Rutter, and south is Story Boulevard
from AG agricultural to NR3 neighborhood
residential neighborhood residential
high density.
>> And a staff report, please.
Mr. Chair, committee, Morgan Dennis from
Planning and Development.
Uh, this zone change is for
approximately 3.43 acres of land
generally located north of Prairie
Avenue, east of Powder House Road and
west of Rutair. This land is requesting
to be changed from AG agricultural to
NR3 highdensity
neighborhood residential high density.
The projected use of this lot is
highdensity senior residential
development. There is a final plat
running concurrent with this zone
change. The future land use map
designates this area as urban
residential.
This designation promotes a number of
residential developments including
multi-unit residential
developments.
The surrounding zoning in the area is LR
low density residential which is Indian
Hills neighborhood which is single
family residentials.
um AG agricultural parcels which are a
holding place until these areas can be
developed and MUB
zone which is currently a parking lot.
On February 2nd, 2026,
the planning commission heard this zone
change and recommended approval. There
has been no public comment regarding
this zone change.
Thank you, Morgan. Questions from the
committee for staff. Questions? Dr.
Renie? Any?
>> No questions, Mr. Chairman.
>> All right. Thank you, Morgan. Uh, we'll
open it up to the public for comment.
>> Mr. Remens. Uh, chairman, city council
members, Brad Emmens, AVI, agent for the
owner, which is section 20 LLC, and the
applicant, which is the Village
Cooperative Senior Housing Center. Um,
before you is a zone change, as Morgan
pointed out, and later on a final plat
that will also dedicate part of Melton
Avenue. Um, there is a site plan that's
also going through the process.
Currently, um, I believe there's 54
units, uh, and a lower level parking
garage. um if if this goes through and
and we get the site plan approved and be
happy to answer any questions. We also
have representatives from there on the
um Zoom meeting if if you have specific
questions for them as well.
>> Thank you, Mr. Questions from the
committee for for uh Mr. Evans. Dr.
Aldrich,
>> I do have one question. Um Chairman
Crave through you. I actually have
several friends who have are purchasing
into this property. Um and um I I think
saying senior housing would probably
give them epoplexy. Um I know that it's
for el or older residents uh with no
children allowed is my understanding. Um
when do you anticipate that they will
break ground or when these will be ready
because some of these individuals are
concerned they're going to die before
it's done.
>> Mr. Mr. Chair through you. I'm going to
let Andrew uh speak to that item. Um, is
there more know what the what the
process is?
>> Um, yes. Uh, this is Andrew Schaefer
with Real Estate Equities Development.
Uh, we're the developer of Village
Cooperative Communities um throughout I
think 12 different states that we've
developed them in. And we're excited to
be pursuing this project. And yes, we
are kind of uh pre-marketing and
pre-elling the the homes in this
project. Uh the goal right now is to get
zoning and city entitlements approvals
um this spring and to break ground this
fall. Uh we would anticipate it taking
about 16 to 18 months to build uh just
depending on weather.
>> Further questions? Further questions.
Any MS? Any other uh public comments?
Jennifer, anyone online?
All right, we will close the public
comments and bring it back up to the
dis. Could we have a motion, please?
>> Move to approve.
>> Second.
>> We have a motion to approve and a
second. Discussion by the committee.
>> I did just want to mention, Chairman
Crave, that these are um I think
sometimes when we talk about senior
housing, we think about the subsidized
senior housing. These are actually
retail market value housing. They're not
subsidized to my knowledge in any way.
So, I wanted to make sure people
understood that.
Thank you. Further discussion. Dr.
Renie.
>> No, Mr. Chairman. Thank you.
>> All right. With uh we have a motion and
a second. Uh all those in favor signify
by saying I.
>> I.
>> Those opposed. The recommendation for
Monday night will be to approve. Next
item, please. Number 14, Ordinance,
second reading, amending the official
zoning map of the city of Cheyenne,
changing the zoning classification for
land located southeast of the
intersection of South Gley Highway and
East Asia Lane from AG Agricultural to
VP Business Park.
>> And a staff report, please. Mr. White,
>> chair, and members of the committee,
Conor White Planning and Development
Department. So, this zone change before
you, it's for a larger parcel that's
down in Bison Business Park. Uh, this
parcel is actually just west of the
Microsoft facility that's down there.
It's currently zoned AG. Um, they are
looking to reszone it to BP Business
Park. Um, Microsoft's parcel and a good
portion of Bison Business Park were
actually recently reszoneed to BP I
believe last July or August, somewhere
around there. Um, so this is basically
an extension of that uh zoning for
redevelopment. The smaller parcel on
here up in the northeast corner is
actually for a pump station for BOPU.
And then the rest of the site, I don't
believe has um to my knowledge has a
current development plan. Um
there might be one, but nothing formal
has been submitted for it. Um,
so this is basically just bringing this
parcel into the BP zone, adding it to
the business park, and allowing for the
redevelopment. Planning Commission did
hear this at their meeting at the
beginning of February. They did
recommend approval, and I'm available
for any questions. Thank you, Mr. White.
Questions from the committee.
Questions?
Hearing? None. We'll open it to the
public for public comment. Any
discussion?
Mr. Emmens?
Chairman, council members, Brad Emmens,
um agent for the owner. Um they are
looking, there is a company looking to
uh move on to this. It was in a holding
zone and so we are getting it into a
zone uh that uh can move forward with uh
the use that they want to use on this
property. Um, I do want to commend the
the governing body and the uh staff with
the change to some of the rules with
community facility fees and everything.
We won't probably have to go through
this holding zone anymore and we can get
this stuff through kind of the first
time. Um, so thank you for getting that
done so that we can kind of plan these
areas better and get things moving along
faster. So
>> be happy to answer any questions.
>> Any questions from the committee? Thank
you. Any further uh public comment?
Anyone online? Jennifer
hearing. No further public comment.
Could we have a motion, please?
>> Move to approve.
>> Second.
>> We have a motion and a second. Further
discussion by the committee.
>> Discussion. Hearing none. All in favor
signify by saying I.
>> I.
>> Those opposed. The recommendation for
Monday night will be to approve. Next
item, please.
>> Number 15, ordinance, second reading,
annexing to the city of Cheyenne,
Wyoming, various
completely surrounded by current city
limits situate in western and southern
Cheyenne, generally located east of I25,
south of the intersection of Wesland
Road and Missile Drive, north of West
and East Allison Road, and east of and
adjacent to North College Drive.
>> And a staff report, please. Mayor
Collins.
>> Mr. Chairman, members of the committee,
for the record, I'm Mayor Patrick
Collins. Uh, Chairman Caggrave, in 2022,
this governing body set a goal to annex
county pockets in Cheyenne. We defined a
county pocket as an unincorporated
county property 100% surrounded by the
city. We annex the first nine groups of
county pockets on schedule to this
point. Today, we start the ordinance
process to annex the final 16 county
pockets we have left. Just a bit of
history. When we started this process,
we looked at our ordinances and made
sure changes to make changes to remove
as many financial impacts as we could.
Today, we don't require improvements
like curb, gutter, and sidewalks. We no
longer require folks to city water and
sewer unless they want to. We know
property taxes will rise a little bit,
our requirement to use city sanitation,
and that there will be some uses on a
property that may not be allowed in the
city.
During the public hearing, we had two
hours of public testimony where members
of the community shared their love of
WildFresh Farm and their concern about
this annexation and how it may affect
their farm operations. I appreciate
their concerns and our staff and I have
been working hard to answer those
questions. First, we plan to zone the
farm agricultural a so the operation
will be zoned by right. I think it
should help their operation.
We developed a definition of an urban
farm. It recognizes what WildFresh Farm
does and it supports their operation
today and it'll support their operation
into the future. It also recognizes the
farm has a retail component where they
sell their products and products from
other farms in our community. We know
the farm has some uses that are
currently not allowed in the city.
Livestock, roosters, discharging of
firearms. State law protects many of
these non-conforming agricultural uses.
It allows the farm to have roosters,
sheep, goats, and dairy cows. It will
not though support the discharge of guns
after annexation.
We have a land use documentation form
where we ask people to help us document
the non-conforming uses so that when
we're all gone, we'll have the uses
memorialized and protected.
We've heard the uh farm's concerns about
potential improvements that they may
have to make to Wal Walters Boulevard
and I spoke with our city engineer to
discuss how that decision would be made.
And maybe I can just start off with it
and I'll give you the the site. Uh,
article 4.3.7 of our UDC talks about you
have to have a peak ingress of 25 cars
per hour, but it also says it has to be
at least 35 mph and have 10,000 cars a
day. It is 35 mph, but they have 5,200
cars a day. Our estimate is it won't
actually reach that part where it would
trigger that until about 2045. But in
2045 when it does uh they would have to
uh and if they changed their use to
create more than 25 cars a day, it would
trigger off-site improvements. Um, I
will share with you also though that
engineer Cobb shared with me that we
have a roundabout going in at um, Fox
Farm and Walters and as part of that
project, the uh, the plans show putting
curb gutter down Waltershide Boulevard
that should go past their property
taking care of that responsibility. Um,
we can't let the water that comes off
the roundabout, we have to direct it
where it goes. Um, we also have a plan
to build Waltershy to a three-lane
section in this area. And so if the
traffic got to the point at the farm,
there would already be a left turn lane
moving into the farm. So the only thing
that seems to be left in in the future
would be maybe the potential of having
to build a deceleration lane as you come
from the north to the south to make a
right-hand turn into the farm.
Chairman Craven and committee members, I
appreciate there's angst
about the city council goal to annex the
remaining pockets. I want to assure you
that our staff has been working to
understand the issues and have been
addressing them. We have three weeks
left before the annexation process is
completed and we will continue to work
uh to address any remaining issues. Uh
Charles and Connor are here. They can
answer any technical questions you might
have. Um, we also have before you uh a
zoning um ordinance today and I would
ask for your support to uh complete this
annexation on time and I'd answer any
questions that you might have.
>> Mr. Mayor, I don't I just have a very
brief you you one time you said 25 cars
per hour. The next time you said 25 cars
per day.
>> I apologize. It is per hour at a peak
hour.
>> Thank you.
>> Yeah. And that is a huge distinction.
>> Yes.
>> Thank you.
>> Uh questions uh for the mayor uh from
the committee. Mr. Chairman,
>> Dr. Renie.
>> Thank you, Mr. Chairman. Um through you
to Mayor Collins, you had said that
we've now come up with an urban farm
definition. Is that do we need to
incorporate that um into either the UDC
or somewhere to or how how are we
intendling
intending on handling that?
>> Mr. Mr. Chairman, our staff will be up
here in just a second, but um uh
I believe uh our planning director, Mr.
uh Bloom, has intentions to put that as
a definition in the UDC with eventually
having an amendment to the UDC that
would memorialize this, but he has the
authority when these kinds of situations
come up to make those changes. A example
that is you have those little libraries
that are uh around our city. Um we
didn't have a way to do that. So he
created a a rule. I don't know if you
call it a temporary rule, but a rule
that sets minimum standards for doing
those. He's going to use that same
process to do this.
>> All right. Thank you, Mr. Chairman.
>> Thank you, Dr. Ren. Further questions
from the committee for Mayor Collins.
>> I just have a comment.
>> Okay. U would that be during step during
the committee time or
>> Okay.
>> Uh Chairman Crave through you. Just
wanted to say I really appreciate all
the um work that the staff and the
mayor's office and um our planning
director have done to um try and resolve
all of these questions and and answer
all of the questions uh that have arisen
over the last few weeks about this. So,
I'm looking forward to hearing about the
urban farm definition and seeing if we
can um find some sort of shared common
ground in order for this to move
forward. Thank you.
>> Thank you,
>> Mr. Chairman. Thank you. Uh Dr. Aldrich,
you know, we have uh for this whole
process from the very beginning looked
to try to mitigate impacts as much as we
can and uh staff has really worked hard
over the last week or 10 days uh in
order to try to do that and they'll
continue to do that through the rest of
this process.
>> Thank you, Mayor Collins. Uh, Director
Bloom or Mr. White, let the boss go
first. Okay.
And chair, members of the committee,
Charles Bloom, planning and development
director. Um, first of all, Connor will
be providing an update in just a second
regarding the rest of this. It's more
than just one property. There's a couple
of them that are there to be discussed,
and he's going to, uh, chat about all of
those. But um I did have a chance to
meet with the nicely recently and we
took a stab at a basically the
documentation of land use and I have
sent this to them. I gave this to them
today right before the meeting after
alerting them it would come. But this is
kind of just a framework of what we
understand. So they're welcome to
provide um additional information,
request modifications so they can
clearly say what is going on on their
property because we don't know exactly.
But it's always good to have at least a
starting point. Um, one thing I would
like, so I'm going to pass this out real
quick to Council Member Leborn.
And that is a double-sided document.
And to answer the question regarding the
what we call a zoning interpretation and
policy statement, um that is an item
that we use to provide clarification
when we have existing definitions,
existing um standards and such that we
can put together and say this is how all
that comes together and this is how it
works. This is this will be on our
unified development code web page as an
informal guidance document as the the
mayor mentioned. We have one for little
free libraries. We also have one that
has recently come out regarding what is
discernible noise when it comes to data
center development standards. The intent
of these documents is to create a
written record of what we anticipate
something to be and how we're going to
move forward. So the the finish line is
not moving or changing mid-process. Once
these go through a sufficient time for
public review, chance for people to
break it, see if something doesn't work
where we might need to tweak it, then
the goal is to move it into the unified
development code as an ordinance which
you would see in the future. Um that
might have some additional standards.
might have different standards that
would be in there, but the goal would be
to follow up with um an ordinance
amendment to codify what is in here. Um
I'm open for any questions you have
regarding this particular element. I
would like Mr. White to discuss the
other elements of this annexation as
well.
>> Um Dr. Renie, before we get go further,
I just want to let you know the handout
shows a u aerial view of of uh the farm
uh delineating various um buildings,
pens, um food stand, uh that type of
thing. Um just so you have that
knowledge. Thank you. Uh
>> thank you, Mr.
>> Dr. Aldrich.
>> I just had one question. Chairman Crave
through you. What is a tire bell
installation?
Chair council member Dr. Aldrich. I did
not know about this until I had a
conversation with the nicely. Um that
basically they are bales of used tires
that are compressed. Um they have a lot
of uh benefits regarding farming and
erosion control. Um I would ask a little
bit more I'd ask for more information
from the nes on how they work but it's
my understand that those are common in
some farming aspects.
>> Thank you. Thank you. Um, Mr. White, did
you want to address us
chair and members of the committee?
Conorweight Planning and Development
Department.
So, I was just going to quickly kind of
run through because this is the
annexation portion. We do have the
assigned zoning, which is the ordinance
after. So, I don't know if you want me
to talk about that during this or if we
do want to make sure those are
separated. Um they're probably going to
blend
uh between the two uh with some of the
discussion, but
I just want to remind everybody there is
more than one parcel in this annexation.
Um we've got at least seven pockets
taking 16 parcels.
Um so the zoning portion I have a lot
more to go over than just uh one parcel
in the annexation. So I I'm more than
happy to split them in two and just talk
about the zoning under the other or I
can just run through everything at once.
Is there preference from the committee?
>> Um
what
uh annexation and zoning all at once.
Does that does that work? Dr. Renie, do
you have a preference?
>> No, Mr. Chairman.
>> Okay, Mr. White, as much as we can,
let's do them together. There might be
when we get to the the zoning, there
might be some additional questions, but
>> perfectly fine. I'm more than happy to
do that.
>> Thank you.
>> All right. So, with the annexation, uh
there is seven pockets, uh totaling 16
parcels. So, we've got, I believe it's
16 different ownerships. There might be
one or two that own one or two of the
lots in that pocket. Um but we do have
multiple. Two of the pockets are uh
railroad rightway.
Um those are actually so that triangle
on this screen if I go back to the first
they're basically over along Waltershide
or not Waltershide uh Westland Road
sorry. Um so the triangle little portion
that is on the left of the screen that
is two residential properties and then a
city-owned parcel that basically gets
used as an alley.
Um,
with those parcels, they are zoned LI.
Um, even for the residences. So, with
those being zoned LI, um, and I believe
that triangle is also LI.
The city does recommend that those be
just basically zoned LI. Um, even though
they have residences on them, they're
already non-conforming technically in
the county. They'll just cons continue
as non-conforming coming into the city.
um that whole area over there is
developed with commercial and light
industrial uses. It's mostly auto
dealerships and things like that. So
having it li those homes ever did
redevelop, they're already zoned
basically for that area.
Railroad uh the railroad portions
including this one. Um
we don't really zone rights of way. We
do have it in there that these just be
zoned whatever they're currently as. In
the county, I believe the triangle was
LI. This one is CB community business.
So, it'll just take on those that
zoning.
Um, all of these parcels are 100%
contiguous to the city, 100% surrounded.
Um, not only the ones that are at the
beginning, but everything through this
annexation, they're all 100% surrounded.
And I might actually just pull up the
zoning map rather than the annexation
maps,
which isn't okay, never mind. My zoning
map isn't really working. Um, so with
parcel 4, uh, this is the farm. Um, 100%
surrounded by city limits, staff does
recommend that this be zoned to AG
agricultural.
Um, at the planning commission meeting,
planning commission's recommendation,
they did want us to re-evaluate that
zone and take a deeper look at it. I did
provide in my memo that's at the
beginning of the packet a little bit
more of our analysis. There's not too
much more analysis we can do. We have
two agricultural zones. We have the AG
zone and the agricultural residential
zone. Um the AG zone actually provides
more agricult or allows for more
agricultural uses
um
than the AR zone and actually gives more
flexibility when it comes to
agricultural uses. So that's why staff
would go with the AG zone as it provides
more of that flexibility and allowance.
The parcel five that is urban
residential low density out in the
county. Uh staff would recommend that
that become MR medium density
residential.
The reason for the MR zone, uh, that is
the closest city zone actually to the
east of the parcel or this pocket. Um,
across the street is AG. Um, and then to
the north, I believe, is community
business. These are all residential
lots. Uh, so staff felt and they're all
developed closer to our MR zoning uh,
for residential. So staff feels that the
MR zone would be the most appropriate
for parcel 5.
Parcel six. This one is up off of Fox
Farm. Um the new the if you're
um familiar with the Fox Farm townhouse
development that's over there. Uh those
new kind of multif family, they're kind
of like town houses. They're all on a
single lot. This parcel is like right
next to that. Um, it is 100% surrounded
by city limits, but it is surrounded by
the NR3 zoning. It's currently zoned LI
out in the county. Um, the current use
of the property is a I believe it's a
telecommunication facility, kind of
their storage. Um, has some warehouses
and things like that on there.
Staff is recommending this just be zone
2 LI. Uh, we took a very deep look at
this one. Uh we looked at seven
different zone districts for this
parcel.
Um trying to figure out really what
would be best because the future land
use map does have this area as mixeduse
residential. Uh surrounded by NR3. There
is community business just to the west.
Uh the county's LU is to the east.
County light industrial is actually to
the south across Fox Farm. So there's a
ton of different zone districts kind of
in the area. and we looked at what would
be best for this parcel. Ultimately, we
believe the LI zone, just giving it what
it has in the county, would be best at
this point. Um, should it sell and want
to redevelop and they want to reszone it
to NR3, staff can always support that
and bring that back toward uh back to
council for a reasonzoning in the
future, but the LI zone does allow them
to continue basically their current use
and allow them to operate as they have
been in the county.
Parcel 7. Um, two of these parcels on
parcel 7 are zoned LI out in the county
and the southernmost parcel is zoned
um, LU, so land use. The two parcels on
the north half um, are developed with a
kind of industrial style use. So staff
does recommend those be zone 2 LI.
So, in the ordinance, we actually did
break this parcel up because we proposed
that the southernmost parcel actually be
zoned to AG. Um, the southernmost
parcel, it does have a residence on it
does look like it has some farm
buildings. Um, we I actually did after
the public hearing speak with the
property owners um about this parcel and
they do have horses. They do want to
continue being able to use it in that
fashion. And again, the AG zone does
have the most flexibility when it comes
to agricultural uses and would allow
them to have horses, as many horses,
they can add horses and all of that. Um,
it is also surrounded by the AG zone out
here. Uh, so staff is fine with the AG
zone going for that southern parcel, but
with the two northern ones, they do have
light industrial uses, commercial uses
on them. So the LI would actually give
them the most flexibility for their
current uses.
So again, planning commission did hear
the assigned zoning at their meeting. Uh
their only change for their
recommendation, they recommended
approval, but they recommended that
staff re-evaluate parcel 4, which would
be the farm. As I noted, we looked
further into it, but again, there's only
two AG or two agricultural zones that
allow agricultural uses. Um so that's
why we believe the AG zone still works
for parcel 4. Otherwise, they recommend
approval for the rest of the various
pockets. Um, and again, with the
annexation, these are 100% surrounded,
um, and are part of council's goal to
annex those 100% surrounded county
pockets. With that, I am available for
questions. I guess actually one note
just in case I get the question that I
usually get. I have not had any further
public comment um on these parcels uh
phone calls or whatnot since last
Monday's meeting besides I guess maybe
the mail chains with uh the nicely but
that other than that I have no further
public comment.
>> Thank you Mr. White questions from the
committee for staff
>> sir
>> Dr. Aldridge.
>> Uh, Chairman Crave, I'm through you. I'm
I'm sorry that I wasn't uh here last
Monday night and so I I heard the
conversation about another parcel that
might fall into the urban farming uh
use. Is that parcel number seven? Is
that the one we're talking about?
>> Mr. Chair, through you. Uh yes. So that
would be the southernmost parcel in um
what is counted as parcel 7 or pocket 7.
Uh that is the parcel. Um, after I heard
their testimony, I hadn't spoken with
them previous or prior to that meeting.
So, I did actually go out into the
hallway and I spoke with them for quite
a while providing additional
information, letting them know we are
recommending they be zoned a which
allows the continuation of basically how
the land has been used. So,
>> thank you.
>> Further questions for staff from the
committee?
>> Mr. Chairman,
>> Dr. Renie,
>> thank you. I have a couple questions for
Connor. Um,
so on going back to parcel 7, did that
become 100% surrounded when we annex
sweet grass?
Mr. Chair, through you?
I would have to look because I believe
the portion that surrounds them isn't
technically part of Sweetgrass's PUD or
part of SweetGrass.
>> Okay. I just
>> I'm getting a thumbs up from Mr. bloom
that yes that
>> that is what made it 100% surrounded.
>> All this time I never realized that was
surrounded but when you I guess look at
how large that annexation was that makes
sense. Going back to parcel number six
um normally if that state ally it would
be required to do a landscaping buffer
between it and the neighborhood that
surrounds it. So if we are initiating
this annexation that am I correct that
buffer will not be required
>> Mr. share through you. If they choose to
redevelop that lot, the buffer would be
required. If they're continuing to use
it as is currently um and they don't
make any changes, they don't submit any
site plans or redevelop it, then no,
they don't have to provide any
additional buffer. But if they do choose
to redevelop it, then we would have to
look at how what how they're
redeveloping it and we may actually
require that buffer.
>> All right. Thank you, Connor. Thank you,
Mr. Chairman. Any further questions from
the committee for staff?
Any anything further? All right, we'll
open it up to the public
public testimony.
Welcome. Please identify yourself for
the record.
>> Okay. Thank you. Uh my name is Chelsea
McCort and I live uh over here on Bent
Avenue.
>> Great. Thank you.
>> Uh first of all, thank you uh Chairman
Crave and the rest of the committee for
being here today. We appreciate you
allowing us to have public commentary to
be able to voice our opinion as members
of the public. Um, one point of
clarification before I chat a little bit
more. Um, when mayor was up here, he
kept referring to the farm as fresh
farm. That is not its name. It's Wfresh
Farm. And so I just wanted to provide
that little bit of clarification in case
you hear multiple names being thrown
around.
>> Thank you.
>> As a note, Worofresh is a farm, but it's
up in Greyel. So anyways, um I also wish
to mention that uh I am speaking on
behalf of WFresh, although I'm not an
owner. Um I've been actively involved in
in uh working through this process with
them. And so if I say we, I am speaking
as an agent of WFresh. Um
>> thank you.
>> Uh yeah, also fun note, I'm a city girl,
so a lot of this is all new to me, too.
And so I'm trying to kind of be in a
position to help advocate for you
because I like government. I like uh
regulations and rules, but to kind of be
that buffer between city and what
everyone else knows and what they might
know as farmers. So just just trying to
help what I can. Um I would also like to
express a lot of gratitude for the
people that have put in a lot of work
regarding the issues surrounding parcel
4. Again, that's that's why fresh. Um
we've had some wonderful meetings with
the uh city planning department
including uh Charles Bloom just this
last Friday. and um we're feeling
timidly optimistic uh but we feel that
we're kind of more at the start and not
at the end. And so the March 9th
deadline is really worrying for us. Um I
I mean I don't think I really need to
explain why we're fighting so hard for
this. Um I feel like that's been
emphasized. The community really values
why fresh as was you know there there's
multiple people wearing green shirts
here and in the previous uh city council
meeting. Um, we also are wanting to
fight for this to make a real difference
for the city of Cheyenne for future
urban agriculture, um, urban farmers,
things like that. Uh, I think could
really help benefit the city of Cheyenne
as it continues to grow. City of
Cheyenne continues to, um, butt up
against more and more rural, urban,
agricultural areas. And so I think that
this is the time to address it now to
get that all sorted out before you
encounter any other future issues that
may arise. Um and we're also speaking to
a degree behalf on parcel 7. Um which is
there's someone else here representing
it as well, but um that that we want to
make sure that any lands that have this
urban agricultural element are properly
incorporated so that it doesn't hinder
their ability. Urban agriculture is
extremely beneficial. It's been shown,
you know, through studies, other uh
groups have incorporated that into their
city zoning. Through this process, even
within this last week, we found out the
city of Casper has had some form of
urban agriculture on their uh zoning
since 1991, which in context was the
year before I was even born. Um, so it's
not a problem that can't be solved, but
it's a problem that should be solved,
and it's a problem I think we don't
rush. Again, which plays back to that
role of the March 9th deadline. Um, one
other thing I'd like to add about the
benefits of of um, urban farming and
urban agriculture is it has the
potential to help educate us city
dwellers about things farm uh, farm
related about things that are very
stereotypical Wyoming. When I went up to
the first time, I was like, why are
there holes all over your property?
Found out it was from chickens. Chickens
like to dig holes and so you just have
to watch where you go. U, my kids
learned that apparently uh, sheep love
the smell of Skittles. They had some
Skittles in the pocket and the sheep up
there just really wanted to get out
those Skittles and were like, "Nope, you
got to take those out." So, there's so
many benefits. Uh, Frontier Days
tourists coming wanting to get a taste
of Wyoming. It's in the middle of the
city. Uh, there's so many great benefits
for it. Um, I I want to clarify that
we're not trying to be up here to
present ourselves to these whiny farmers
who don't ever, you know, let up against
the city council fighting for justice
and truth. Um, we're fighting because we
are a benefit for the community and we
are have been told repeatedly that
nothing will change. And while nothing
may initially change, that's not true.
There are multiple ways that we will
change through increased fees and
permits, increased amount of time to
have to handle all these documentations
and things. And it's not something that
isn't unworkable, but it's things that
need adaptation so that it isn't
affecting WFresh too much that it
ultimately will run them out of
business. Um,
sorry, I'm seeing where I was in my
notes of where I want to go here. Um,
so, uh, it takes us more time sometimes
to reply to these things that the city
is bringing forth to us. Um, we again
are not familiar with city codes. I've
had to learn so many new terminologies
in city codes in this process and I work
multiple hours every single day to try
to make sure that that we're bridging
that gap between you guys and we want to
work with you. We want to work with the
city and we're really excited to do it
so that we can make such a positive
difference. Um but that being said again
the city can come turn something around
in a day or two and that may take us a
week because we're trying to run a farm.
It's a pretty extensive you know
process. Um, the Nicely homeschool their
children. Uh, David has a day job. Um, I
I'm just volunteering my time. I'm a
stay-at-home mom and this isn't my job
either. And so, um, if we're spending
this much to to only slowly pump out
what we need to, it's an indication that
it we can't keep up with this rate, but
we need to keep up with this rate so
that the city can do it correctly and
thoroughly and have it done once without
needing to go back and amend every like
two weeks. Okay. Um so
um so for instance like just taking a
second to look at the a zoning within
the U urban devel United united
development code. My apologies. Um a
zoning has currently three like
subdefinitions and I know that uh
Charles Bloom presented and mentioned
mayor mentioned as well that they're
planning on adding a different
definition as well regarding urban
farms. Um which is great. uh but that to
to get into the codes themselves is
going to take time. For instance, we
would want that in the codes before
we're fully annexed so that it has um
it's there and it has addressed the
issues that we are concerned about. Uh,
a zoning also in general we feel is kind
of problematic um, just because it it is
also designated as a holding zone. And
so when people think of ag, when city
officials look at agg, they aren't
necessarily thinking immediately that
this is indeed a farm, they may be
thinking this is a holding zone for
later city development. And I think it's
clear that we make sure that there's a
distinct difference for for everybody
for the people who are and are not
familiar with the with what a means in
the United Development Code, unified
development code. I apologize. I'm
really bad about that. Um we I mean
these last like two days I've been
sitting down with the nicely and we've
been working on a master list. Mind you
some of these have been answers and some
of these haven't. But to begin with as a
rough draft we have over 68 questions.
Again I would say probably half of them
have been addressed and half of them the
the other half of those that haven't
been addressed are pretty
straightforward answers like do
livestock guardian dogs um does leash
law apply to them? That's a yes or no.
But the problem is when we ask those
questions at the moment, we ask them and
we're getting a call this department,
call that department, call this
department. And if we do that, that
obviously takes a lot of time. We're not
particularly fast. Um, and when we ask
for the city to do it, we're not really
getting the direct answers probably
because we're mainly working with the
city planning department and that's not
necessarily in their purview to do it.
And so coming together with some sort of
liaison or agent would be really
beneficial in this case. Can I interrupt
quickly? Have Have we received that list
of 60 questions?
>> Not yet. I, like I said, this is the
rough draft. Um, hopefully we'll be
getting it out in the next day or so as
a nonformalized rough draft. Um, we can
send that list of questions out, but we
also want to look through the answers we
have received and kind of be able to
check some of those off, too. It's a
process. It will be coming to you guys
shortly, though. I I can promise you
that.
>> Thank you. Um that also I think finally
really just go boils down to that this
is not an unsolvable problem and that
what we're just asking is to make sure
that we're not rushing this. Um that as
the city has stated they want to work us
work work work with us. So, let's work
together. But the the timeline of March
9th is likely not realistic to make sure
that those um United Development Code
zoning changes have been put into
effect. Um to make sure that we have
everything written out because that's,
you know, anyone who's a lawyer or
anyone knows the importance of having it
all together and all documented. And so
that's also a big goal of ours so that
there isn't a question when leadership
changes, has has the answers changed?
Have the answers changed? Um, so, uh, I
I would like to go back for one second
with Kathy Emmens who mentioned, um, at
the end of the city council meeting, uh,
regarding Wresh on Monday, uh, that you
they she asked us to trust her and we
definitely want to trust you guys. We
want to trust that the desire to work
with us to make sure everything is right
happens. But it's hard. It's hard when
it feels like we're being rushed and
when we have the questions, we're not
getting the answers right away or we're
getting the answers and it's requiring
us to do more work, but it's not
unsolvable. Again, we're feeling timidly
optimistic. People are starting to work
together with us. And so, basically,
we're just asking for more time and we
also don't want to hold up all the rest
of the parcels. So, taking us out and
handling it separately, I think, would
be also well advised. So, those are kind
of my thoughts. Thank you for for
allowing me to speak.
>> Further public discussion.
>> Welcome.
>> Hi, David Nicely. David Nicely 200
Waltershide. Um,
yeah, we're timidly optimistic. Um, and
um, I appreciate what has been said. Um,
I guess
I I keep hearing that March 9th is an
absolute deadline,
that it cannot be postponed.
I'm told that it will not be postponed.
Um,
I don't know whether it's appropriate,
but I have four city council people
here, and my question of each of you is
why not?
Um, and I'd appreciate a response, but
I'm not Elvis. I won't sing and I won't
dance, but I will ask you, don't be
cruel.
Um, my health is suffering.
I'm facing the biggest health crisis
I've had in my 60 almost 60 years.
I've used up all of my vacation for this
year to deal with this process.
I wasn't even notified until January
28th.
My children are suffering because the
cortisol levels in my household dealing
with
the perceived threats at least
that
we won't be able to stay in the home
they're born in um
feels really real to us. My wife's
health is suffering.
Um,
we didn't even get a phone call to ask
us when it would be convenient to have
this discussion.
We grow vegetables in green houses. This
is the This is a day
spent here instead of planting and we're
behind schedule.
It's cruel for the city to destroy our
fences
and we spend a year trying to get them
to promise to fix them and then not fix
them and then put us in a position where
on March 9th we can't defend our
livestock.
Um,
it's just cruel to without asking us
about schedule to give us a month and a
half of crisis and tell us it can't be
put off.
It's cruel that I have to spend vacation
money to pay people to do work that I
should be doing instead of being here.
Um,
so why
this is complicated stuff?
Um,
we miss M Mr. Bloom was at at our farm
Friday was it?
And we talked about triggers for curbs,
gutters, and sidewalks on Walters
Boulevard. And I don't know why Dur
Avenue was excluded from the discussion
or the building of Jefferson Street
through which is on the maps was
excluded from the discussion but Mr.
Bloom told me there are more triggers
than the single trigger that the mayor
said was in the news.
Um so we don't even know what the right
answers are. Um so why um is it fair to
ask um every c city councilman why March
9th?
Um
and then
just a cruel process.
Um at the city council meeting the other
night, the city council went back to
staff and asked them questions.
Nobody came back to us and asked us
questions. You must have questions for
us. I'll be happy to answer any of them.
Tom, you'd be happy to answer them. Um,
so please, if you have any questions,
ask. Um, and I realize I sound angry.
Um, in some senses I am, but really I'm
just desperate. Um, you know, protect
our home, save our farm. Um, and if you
have a chance to alleviate our concerns,
please.
Thank you.
Does anyone on committee have questions
uh for Mr. Nicely at this point?
Questions? Anyone? Dr. Renie?
>> No, Mr. Chairman.
>> Okay. At this at this point, I think
we're okay with that.
Public comment, please. Yes, ma'am.
>> Hello, Kathy Sigiano. Um, I too have the
same question that Mr. Nicely asked you.
Why um is there a a health and safety
risk? Because to me it sounds like
there's a health and safety risk in his
home with him and his wife. I am really
trying to fight back some emotion cuz I
don't want to stand up here and look
like some girl that's going to cry
over people I don't even know. I didn't
even ever meet them until this happened
a month ago till I saw a post on a
Facebook page.
It is cruel
and the community thinks it's cruel that
you're giving them such a short amount
of time to come up with answers that you
can't even answer or that our city in a
whole cannot answer. It is breaking my
heart to have conversations with this
man of him telling me that they may just
give up and sell their property.
Do you want that? Do you want future
businesses to do that and think that way
of our of our city? Because I don't. I
care about this city. Otherwise, I would
never come to a freaking meeting.
That's all I have to say.
>> Thank you. Further public discussion.
Yes, sir.
Donald Carrer Cheyenne Wyoming. Thank
you guys. Appreciate it. Um I'm going to
echo the same sentiment.
Um my question to you guys and to
anybody else that's involved in that is
we've heard phenomenal testimony on both
ends. Um I I think the city council,
this is the first time coming in here
with the exception last um last Monday.
I I get it. You know, there there's
things that you guys are looking at. You
guys got your lens. They got their lens.
The the public's going to have their
lens to look at it. Um, echoing what
they just said, man, that's crazy to
hear a grown man like
beg. Okay, that that takes a lot. It
does. And and when you see these people
out in the street, when you see them,
you know, in the grocery store, when you
pass them, you know, in the supermarket
or something like that, it's it's it's
detrimental to them. That's the city's
going to go on. and the city's going to
be able to have plenty of opportunities
to build and rest and everything else.
This family and their their stuff won't.
So, I'm going to say the same thing. Why
why why are we in a rush to do this?
Like, I I get it. Like, there's
timelines. There's other things. You
don't want to hold up other business. We
get it. But clearly, the the public has
has spoken for optics, too. You know,
there's a lot of people that don't have
trust in city council. There's a lot of
there's so many different moving pieces
to it. I don't understand why there's a
rush. And and again, you know, it's
when when I think about it in the sense
of, yeah, you guys might have all the
rights to do it. City, the development,
all the engineering, you guys might have
completely all the reasons to annex
this. Say we don't care, but do you need
to do it? That's the question because
you guys have to go home and wrestle
with it. Maybe you guys do, maybe you
guys don't. That's a real life family. I
mean, during COVID, we had people commit
suicide because they couldn't operate
their business. anybody wants that on
their hand and I'm not suggesting that
and nor am I trying to guilt trip but
that's the reality of it you know I
don't know these people either but it
frustrates me that I mean earlier there
was something that upset me with the um
the memorial thing why do we always got
to interfere with government whether
it's city state federal into certain
things that really doesn't matter like I
I get it they've I've heard arguments
about they can't shoot stuff in city
limits to protect their property well
that's an easy fix life traps and
everything else. But that's something
for them to work out. I just that's hard
for me to swallow as a human being that
sometimes I could be very abrasive, but
I'm also very sensitive to hear a grown
man beg. That's that's crazy. I mean,
you guys have a decision to make. I pray
I pray that you guys make that right
one. And let's again, not rush it. Not
rush it. To me, it sounds like city
count or at least Mr. Mayor. I get it.
He has a vision. You know, he stood up
here and he testified that, you know,
when he came on board, he had all these
annexations he wanted to do. And and
that to the public looks horrible
because the public starts to look like,
"But geez, that could be my property."
You know, we've heard testimony last
Monday where there was people that were
talking about Don Edmunds, um I think is
his name from the security company that
said at the time when he was here, there
was nothing out there, but as the city
grows, we're going to encroach on all
different stuff like that. you know,
just I pray you guys be be soft heart
about it. Thank you.
>> Thank you very much. Appreciate that. Uh
further comment. Yes, sir.
>> Welcome.
>> Gabriel Pac, fifth generation Cheyenne
resident and small business owner and
ham radio operator. More on the
relevance of that in a second. Um first
I would like to thank the city staff uh
the city staff particularly Mr. Bloom
and Mr. white um for examining the codes
and working through some of the legal
definitions and some of those gray areas
that we might not quite be sure about.
And I spoke last meeting about the
possibilities for Cheyenne to be leading
the way in this integrated urban
agriculture movement and they observed
that count Casper has had something to
this effect since ' 91 and other cities
have that there are signposts pointing
the way but specifically to Cheyenne as
you observe Mr. labor quite astutely.
This is the first time you may have seen
it in your career, but there will be
others. Um, but we have the opportunity
to perhaps take it a step further. But I
thought I might sort of come at it from
a couple different perspectives as to
the particularly in terms of time
frames. Um, small agricultural and farms
like this,
they tend to work on a scale more in
years or decades. And the reason being
is because on this scale they treat the
farm more in terms of an organism or
perhaps even as my friend Chris Keatley
mentioned an ecosystem
rather than a factory. U Gabriel Brown
is a gentleman out of Montana who does
an excellent job uh delineating the
differences and about how he did that
for further if you guys are more
interested in what that entails. But
when you're dealing with ecosystems,
sudden changes can be very detrimental.
Um, and when you're dealing with
organisms, the same thing. Harsh and
quick changes. So, that's one of the
reasons that we're talking about a
longer time frame than perhaps March
9th. Because in a factory, you can flip
a switch, make a change like that, and
you're okay. But when you're dealing
with something in terms of looking in a
scale of decades,
things tend to move a little bit slower.
We saw in our nation's history an
example of this the German farmers
versus the uh English farmers say in
Pennsylvania where the English would
clear out vast sws of forest and then
farm whereas the German farmers might be
stuck on the same 5 acres for three or
four generations. So that's sort of the
perspective where these farmers are
coming on on a small scale as to why
they might be talking in a different
time frame like that. It's just sort of
things move at a different pace from a
ham radio perspective. I I worked for a
shop here in town for four years making
antennas. I've been a ham radio operator
for 11 years, I believe. And I just saw
some parallels between what we're seeing
now versus the ham radio movement.
Particularly during World War I, it had
become apparent that in the war, radio
was the technology of the future. It
worked better than the telegraph wires
of the Old West. It was clunky. We
didn't understand it as best as we
could, but it was obvious there was
opportunity there. Congress did
something kind of unexpected was where
they cut out a space protected from
government and commercial interests
where the amateur operators could
operate almost freely with only minimal
oversight from the government and the
Federal Communications Commission and
they could begin experimenting with this
technology. In the last century, we've
seen that what that has brought us, this
free operation of radio technology
has brought us innovations and
inventions that have built industries,
empowered nations, bolstered economies
and saved countless lives. During
Katrina alone, only we know at least a
thousand operators were helping with
that. So, how does this translate? is
that in the same way we see these
innovations done on small scale local
scale decentralized urban farms. They
have already in the last arguably since
innovated solutions to things that major
farms are struggling with. Lack of
access to fertilizer, erosion, lack of
soil health, uh blight uh treatment
resistant blight and pests. Things like
this have already been innovated on
these small scale farms. So my
encouragement to the city of Cheyenne,
it seems like we are making incredible
progress. And to echo what they said,
timidly optimistic, I think that on a
larger time frame,
the city could avail itself of these
innovations
brought to the people that are arguably
some of the best of us, the ones that
tie their lives and livelihood to nature
and to providing food for the rest of
us. I understand from the city
perspective that there are other things
to be done. there's a there's a balance
to be had.
I think that at le I I hope that I've
been able to at least bring a separate
perspective that there's opportunity for
economic growth and development here as
well. Um and I'm thankful for you guys
for hearing us out. You I feel that
we've made great progress here and this
is my first involvement with city
politics, but I um I think that Cheyenne
is doing us proud and thank you guys.
Thank you, Gabriel.
Further public comment.
Welcome.
>> Hello.
>> Hi.
>> I'm Roxy Havvel. I'm owner of like Track
7, the lower or the southern part of
Track 7 with the barn. We have the
original
>> uh one of the original barns in Cheyenne
Dairy Barns. Um, we just wanted to let
everybody know that we also see the same
kind of stress that this other family is
coming on because we do want to keep our
fam or our home as much as agriculture
as we can. Um, currently there is
nothing surrounding us other than the
two other plots that have NPT and
Coca-Cola. Um, we are do have the the
farm. Um, so I just want you guys to
know like what's the rush into making
our plot so much of a city. Um, it was
recommended that you guys are going to
um do agriculture for us, which would be
fantastic, but we want to know what's
really the guidelines of what we have to
follow because the guidelines that we
have from the packet that was sent to
us, it's not really a guideline for us.
It doesn't make sense. I did some
calling this week. Nobody has a plan for
our our property as far as tapping in,
not pop tapping in, doing this, not
doing that. So there's just no actual
guideline and so we would like to sit
down and actually have a guideline of
what's going to happen in the next 10 10
15 years for our property. Um can't say
that everything's going to be built
around us exactly. Um because from what
we know, our the property around us is
still private property. Um, so we're
just we we just wanted you guys to know
that we feel the same stress. We don't
know whether to just sell our property
or just roll over and let you guys do
what you want to do. That's not fair to
us. Um, we paid a lot of money to buy
that property
um to keep it the the bar to keep the
barn the way that we want to keep it. We
do want to restore that barn to almost
original state. Um, but if we're
have to pay all these fees to do this or
do that or however you guys want to do
it, it it's not feasible for us. It
would financially destroy our family if
we were to tap into the city. Um, so I
just wanted you guys to take that into
consideration, too.
>> Thank you.
Further discussion.
Welcome.
>> Hi, I'm Tommy Nicely, owner of WFresh,
and I just want to reiterate um some
things that have been mentioned.
Um I'm very grateful to have the
opportunity to live in a place where
government is accessible and listens.
And
I really do believe we just started. Um
Mr. Bloom even came out to our farm on
Friday to try to understand some things
and um did have kind of uh
recommendation and asked our input. Um
and I mean I just want to proceed very
careful carefully. Um
again timidly optimistic I think we're
starting to get the ball rolling in the
right direction.
Um, I'm thankful that we finally got a
code on what would trigger road
improvements, but we still have
questions like what would trigger us to
have to hook up to water and sewer? Um,
which a laws can supersede city laws?
Um, a big one we still haven't been
answered. How do we protect livestock?
Again, I'm very naive. I'm just a
farmer, so I'm used to just sitting down
with people, discussing things, and
making compromises.
Um, I have questions. Can we even amend
the UDC before March 9th annexation?
That's something I'd want to see in
place before I was annexed. Um,
yeah, like what even the talk about
triggering for a turn lane. Um
we got an estimate for that and that
would be at least a h 100,000.
Um we just want to proceed carefully. Um
we're are working on a list. I don't
know if it would be possible to get a
liaison. So we have multiple questions.
I understand it's more than one
part of the government that has purview
over. Um and I think some of the
confusion is I feel like people are
saying we are answering but just on one
day we got three answers and I think it
was for triggering road improvements
three different answers from three
different parts of the government
and it's it's like whooilly we need to
figure this out before we get annexed
and I don't know if we can have a
liaison or just have a meeting of the
council to sit down and have one working
document with our questions being
addressed with where it is written in
the code um for us to proceed.
And then I would also like to say please
please please this is just annexation.
There is no need for slander
or for dangerous rhetoric. Um we don't
need to overexaggerate things.
um that is just not helpful in
proceeding.
>> Thank you. Appreciate it. Further public
comment. Anyone online?
>> Yes, sir.
>> Yeah. I'm Richard Lyall. I live in
Cheyenne. I'm not representing anybody
else, but I've listened to the
discussions and I have not heard uh why
there is a benefit to the city from
doing this annexation. That the most I
heard is the map of the city will be
more aesthetically pleasing if they're
not little spots in the middle that are
not the same color. Um and here you know
I appreciate that city has done a lot of
work uh for almost four years uh uh but
they did most of that without even
talking to the uh residents you know
from uh 2022 until uh
>> sir we've had we've had public meetings
on every annexation.
>> Yeah. Until
>> we've had public meetings at every one
of them.
>> Yeah. until July 29th
between
>> I'm sorry
>> there were nobody reached out to the the
people. So um you know it is you know
Mr. Bloom's department says that this
annexation is consistent with the
state's plan and so it is. But uh it's
up to the governing body to decide
whether or not they want to uh do the
annexation. And looking at this is not
just a plot of land. It's a home and a
business. And I'm concerned that we need
sources of food that are not owned by
the corporations
uh like Walmart and whatever. and a
place where
farmers and ranchers in the region can
sell their food without going through uh
corporate uh uh big corporations that
are monopolizing the distribution of
food. I don't like it when uh there are
four four meat packers
that controlled
um between 85 and 90% of all the meat
sales in the United States. And of those
four, two are foreignbased.
I don't like the uh people's liberation
army of China controlling
our food supply. So
I would say that
um
you know do not constrict the uh um a
small local distributor of locally grown
food from operating as they are. Um and
that's my opinion. Thank you.
>> Thank you. Thank you Richard. Further
public comment.
Councilman Moody.
>> Thank you, Mr. Chairman. Through you,
uh, for the record, Mark Moody, Shine
City Council War 3. Uh, really great
public comment. Really great public
comment from our constituents. Um, to
start with that again, I've always been
opposed if property owners are against
annexation. Okay? I've always been
consistent on that. Remember too,
Cheyenne is rooted in agriculture. We
are rooted in agriculture. A lot of us
have some even minimal experienced
agriculture and also the hardworking
aspect. One thing that u I would say
probably is a very you know hard
deadline. I think we need to give more
time or just not annex these two
properties. That would probably be the
best so that way we can define better
what urban farming is. We can define
better you know what's allowed what's
not allowed because that is a very small
window as we know in government. And I
know we've talked about trust us again.
If we do the will of the people, then I
think we can gain trust. So let's do
what they say. I mean to me that would
be the best way if we want to gain that
trust. And that's why I did provide and
again some of you in the public have it
but for people watching this substitute
I did on my own and I did a little
fashion by crossing out with a pen. If
you look on page two, it was to get rid
of um the uh annexation there, parcel
four. And then we number five to four
and then simply on page three, uh cross
out parcel 7,
you know, that contain 4.94 acres. I'm
not too sure about. I don't know if it's
for the whole all the parcels or just
that one. But again, we can always add
in some there for the other parcels. But
that would be my recommendation so it
can be slowed down. That would be the
best way to slow it down so we actually
can define urban farming,
okay, in defining our things codes. But
that's just my perspective and uh I'll
stand for questions.
Any questions?
Dr. Renie, any questions?
>> No, Mr. Chairman.
>> Thank you.
>> Thank you. Thank you, Councilman.
Further public comment in the room or
online?
>> Yes, sir.
Mr. Chairman, committee members, my name
is Steven Love. I own a house roughly
two blocks to the west of the Nicely in
Ward One. Um, I'm here to voice support
for the owners of Pocket 4, the Nicely,
and the southernmost property of Pocket
7. It would be my recommendation to the
committee to remove pocket 4 and the
southernmost parcel of pocket 7 until an
urban farm zoning definition can be
codified and reflected in the zoning
regulation with such protections as the
increase in livestock numbers adding new
livestock animals potentially drilling
new wells and clearly stated allocations
for construction of agriculture related
structures and fences without the need
to file permitting with the city.
The planning department has a trust me
bro attitude towards future site plans
and I think that the government needs to
provide more formal protections to the
properties such as the nicely for the
sake of future land owners who wish to
protect their land use in the future as
the city expands. I don't think a
promise to place an informal
memorialization of the urban farm
definition is adequate to protect the
nicely and their farm. One reason reason
given for the necess necessity of
annexation is a health is health and
safety. However, Sheriff Kak explained
that there is agreements with the city
to provide emergency services to the
property um last Monday. So, it seems to
me that there is no necessity to annex
before these provisions and protections
can be codified into law. Another note
is why the city council would not
install a deceleration lane and install
city tie-ins to utilities during the
construction of the roundabout on Fox
Farm as a sign of good faith by the city
council to the Niclley's. This would be
a negligible cost to the city and would
serve to reassure that the Nicely may be
able to operate their business long into
the future and their children's future.
Again, I'd like to say I live close
enough to the farm to see it to come
from my kitchen and I do not feel there
is any threat to my health and safety.
Thank you.
>> Thank you, Stephen. Further public
comment in the room or online?
Public comment
hearing none. Public comment will be
closed. We'll bring it back up to the
dasis. Uh if we could have a motion, we
can discuss it.
Is there a motion to approve?
So moved. Is there a second?
>> Second.
>> We have a motion and a second.
Discussion from committee.
>> Move to postpone.
>> We do. Do Do we need to do that as an
amendment? We have no just a motion. It
requires a second.
>> We have a motion to postpone. Is there a
second?
A second. Hearing none. The motion
fails. Further discussion from the
committee. Uh Councilman Leborn.
as we begin this process and uh
certainly having been
involved in these matters for some time,
one of the things that I think is really
important that I that I hear frequently
is is there equity and even approach to
many different situations
and that is I I think key here um
are those situations where people can
keep their livestock
how are they doing? What uh what
considerations have come up?
So that's a a important consideration to
me. I would I would have to say Mr.
Chairman that there's a lot to know and
a lot to learn and I certainly look
forward to doing that.
I don't know if I need to learn about
ham radio.
I don't know if I need to learn about uh
corporate agriculture.
Um I definitely believe that we need
options
that um certainly the state of Wyoming
and
other uh agricultural
uh regulators have uh really relaxed and
changed some of the regulation so that
people can do more themselves. I I
definitely believe that uh that
opportunity, if it exists, should be uh
allowed.
I hear over and over and over again
about questions that aren't being
answered.
I look forward to a review of that so
that I can look at and understand what
these questions are and how they're
answered because that's certainly the
case um
in any annexation in any action that we
take. So uh the reason I didn't support
uh the postponement is from my
perspective we're beginning a process
here that is well recognized and is
operated with many different parcels. So
certainly there is that opportunity. I
look forward to uh learning more from
Mr. Bloom about uh the questions he has
been asked and answered and certainly uh
there's a lot to know here. I look
forward to learning. Um, and I certainly
look forward to um
possibly we can come up with uh some
policies that would benefit other
individuals that might want to do
something like this on their
property. That's uh I know things change
and hopefully we're going to learn from
it, but really to postpone at this point
is uh not logical to me. I don't I don't
know enough to postpone or not postpone.
And I can see that I'm going to have to
sort through a lot. And I hope that it's
factual
and driven by logic
and fact
because um
>> obviously this is a decision that's
going to be um have a lot of resonance
throughout the community for some time.
I think we're going to have to uh be
able to explain what and how we do
this process. and I look forward to
learning more about it and uh being able
to make a more informed decision. But
I've heard some things today that I'm
going to be checking up on and try to
learn more about. Um I definitely look
forward to uh
really learning more about this whole
movement. I mean I I believe it is a
movement and I believe that it is
something that uh
many people are interested in including
me. Um, so it might be that someone
dislikes
corporate agriculture,
but that doesn't necessarily mean that
uh we don't want to be clear in any
regulations
and any uh
considerations that come with that
annexation
because that that it's an example for
others and it certainly is example for
us. So, uh that's the reason I'm in
favor of moving this on. Uh obviously,
postponements can come later if the need
is demonstrated, but I didn't see any I
didn't hear any need demonstrated today
since we are uh
not very far along in this and certainly
I'm not far enough along to make an
informed decision. I look forward to
doing that. Thank you, Mr. Chairman.
>> Thank you, Councilman. Further
discussion. Councilman uh through you
>> Dr. Aldridge.
>> Um I I um
I am going to be a no vote today if I am
able to vote. Um I do have to leave for
another appointment here within the next
seven or eight minutes. But I appreciate
everyone's comments that has um have
made comments. I it's frustrating, I
think, for us as a council to hear that
people um may have a belief that we
haven't um followed this process on all
of the annexations we've done. And I
should say it wasn't just the mayor's
goal. It's been a goal of the council um
to do these annexations in these
pockets. Um and for a variety of
reasons, which um I've never heard
included uh aesthetically pleasing maps.
Um but um I think that all of these have
been noticed um in the newspaper and
follow the same process and procedure
that our planning department has offered
um for each one of these annexations
with a public meeting followed then by a
public hearing and then followed by
committee meetings and council. So um I
I don't believe that there's I believe
there's a reason to postpone because I
think the questions need to be answered
and I think that that needs to be done
before we move forward. Um I find um I
was I did ask about the cotification of
the um urban farm definition and was
assured that that was something that
could be done administratively um so
that it would not have to be uh codified
before we did the annexation. But I
still think there are a lot of questions
that have gone unanswered. Um so for
that reason I'm going to be a no vote
today. I'm hoping we can get the answers
um to everyone that's involved. um
before the third and final reading so
that um people can um feel safe and
secure in their homes and and and be
able to operate their businesses.
>> Thank you. Further discussion?
Further discussion hearing? None. All in
favor signify by saying I.
>> I.
>> Opposed.
>> No.
>> The recommendation for Monday night will
be to approve. Next item, please.
Number 16, Ordinance, second reading,
amending the official zoning map of the
city of Cheyenne, establishing the
zoning classifications of AG,
Agricultural, MR, medium density
residential, CB community business, and
LI light industrial for land annex to
the city of Cheyenne, generally located
east of I25, south of the intersection
of Wesland Road and Missile Drive, north
of east west and east Allison Road, and
east of and adjacent to North College
Drive.
staff report. I think we've heard a lot
of it already, but anything else?
>> Just up here to basically state that
I've gone through the zoning that staff
is recommending. Um, and then just as a
quick note, just for the future, um, if
the annexation ever is postponed, this
item would also need to be postponed
with that because it follows the
annexation. I know that's not what
happened here at committee, but just as
a note for future, just in case there
was these two have to run together,
otherwise we're zoning property that's
not annexed. Thank you. Other than that,
I am available for any further
questions.
>> Questions for staff from the committee.
Questions?
Hearing? None. We're talking about
zoning. Uh we'll open it up to the
public for comment. Public comment on
the zoning
comment. Jennifer, anything online?
Uh, hearing no public comment. Could we
have a motion, please?
>> So moved.
>> Second. Is there a second?
>> Dr. Renie?
>> No, Mr. Chair. Oh,
>> is there a second for the motion?
>> Yes. Yes,
>> we have a motion.
>> We have a motion and a second.
Discussion on the zoning
>> discussion hearing. None. All in favor
signify by saying I.
>> I.
>> I. Those opposed. Recommendation for
Monday night will be to approve. Next
item, please.
>> Number 17. Resolution expressing the
support of the governing body for the
inclusion of Laramie County Property ID
number
14663133500500
in the downtown development district.
>> And the staff report, please. Welcome.
>> Thank you. Uh Sophia Mazize, uh Downtown
Development Authority Executive
Director. For the record, let me share
my screen here.
No, I think I got it.
Right.
On November 18th, 2025, staff received
the petition from Rahul Dami,
representative of Don Mender Singh and
Sura Kumari, uh, property owners of 2100
Snyder Avenue for inclusion of property
within the downtown development
district. This property is contiguous to
the downtown district along Snyder
Avenue. The inclusion of this property
would would include all adjacent rights
of way, including but not limited to
Snyder Avenue on the east side, West
21st Street on the south side, and the
adjacent alley on the north side. This
would allow DDA funds to be used on
improvements within the adjacent right
ofways rights of way as well as to
collect mil levy from the property.
Inclusion of this property advances the
DDA statutory purpose to prevent blight
and support property values within the
central business district according to
Wyoming state statute 159-201
at SEC. Expanding the district would
allow targeted infrastructure and
property improvements through existing
DDA programs, improving functionality
and visual appeal while supporting
private investment.
This inclusion is also part of the DDA's
goal to help stimulate economic
activity, attract new businesses, and
support job creation, particularly in
light of the Reed Rail project and the
increased demand that is expected for
nearby properties. It also supports a
more cohesive and strategic approach to
redevelopment, aligning with the 2024
plan of development and the West Edge
goals in the area plan.
Additionally, this expansion creates an
opportunity for future collaboration
along the Snyder Avenue corridor,
strengthening West Edge revitalization
efforts, advancing brownfield
mitigation, and reinforcing a key
gateway into downtown Cheyenne. If the
governing body approves the resolution
before the committee today, the um an
ordinance amending the downtown district
boundary will be followed for the
governing body approval later on. This
process is following the procedure for
inclusion of additional land in the
district as outlined in Wyoming statute
15-9-223.
And at its regular board meeting on
January 15, 2026, the DDA board
recommended approval of the petition for
the inclusion of 2100
Snider in the DDA district to be
considered by the governing body. Staff
recommends approval of the resolution
expressing the support of the governing
body for the inclusion of this property
2100 Snyder Avenue into the downtown
development district. And the
representative for the petitioners is
here today on Zoom to answer any
questions. I also stand for questions.
>> Thank you, Sophia. Questions from the
committee or staff?
Questions?
U doesn't doesn't appear to be any.
We'll open it up to the public for
comment. Public comments.
Public comments. Anything, Jennifer?
All right. Hearing none, we'll close
public comment. We'll I'll ask for a um
uh I move approval. Moved by Councilman
Labour for approval. Is there a second?
>> Second.
>> We have a second. Discussion by
committee. Councilman Labour.
>> Uh thank you, Mr. Chairman. Um,
this is a example, I think, of a
property that I've certainly used many
times. Uh, they don't sell gas anymore,
I don't think, but it's sort of a
neighborhood, uh, market type of
situation.
And certainly, uh, has been there for a
long time. And uh I think that this
conceivably could help the property
owner or whomever might that might be
passed along to to uh
join in on what is our
agonizingly slow improvement of that
area.
Um, and I would point out that obviously
what comes with this is uh the payment
of the mill levy to the downtown
development authority for the purpose of
uh improvement. So I speak in favor of
this and I hope that when we look at it
uh we can really understand why those
property owners want to come into the
district and participate in those
activities. But Mr. Chairman, I have to
say that uh the anticipation of the
benefits that need to flow from our
project there. uh need to start moving
so that this can actually
uh
give these individuals an opportunity
within the next few years to uh
improve their business, their property.
And I speak as a uh long longtime
representative of Ward One in this
neighborhood. And um there have been
uh some good changes uh and not
necessarily right there, but nearby.
But it really is time for us to uh
follow through on the decisions that
we've made and the plans that we've made
and the plans that the DDA has just
made. Um I
Mr. Chairman,
I I I speak in favor of this inclusion.
And I think it'll benefit uh those
individuals
who own it and the neighborhood. But it
really truly it is time to stop planning
and start doing
in that neighborhood with the Reed
Avenue corridor.
Thank you. Thank you. Further
discussion.
Discussion hearing. None. We have a
motion and a second. All in favor
signify by saying I.
>> I.
>> I. opposed.
The recommendation for Monday night will
be to adopt. Next item, please.
>> Number 18 resolution authorizing the
mayor and the city clerk to sign a final
plat for village cooperative city of
Cheyenne Larmy County, Wyoming, located
north of Prairie Avenue, east of Powder
House Road, west of Ruter and south of
Story Boulevard.
>> And a staff report, please.
>> Morgan Dennis, Planning and Development.
Um, so this is the plat that is
following that zone change I spoke about
earlier. Um, this is a plat for 1.4.1
acres of land and will be known as lot
one block one village cooperative.
The land proposed is the lot proposed is
buildable
and is considered MD1 per the UDC. There
is an exception to this plat. Um, this
plat takes on is located within an
oversized block which requires uh some
sort of easement to break up that plot
block. Um, an extension of Milton Street
was dedicated on this plat. Um, the
extension will connect with other
streets as the area continues to
develop.
uh or
February 2nd, um the planning commission
heard this plat and recommended approval
of the preliminary plat with the
exception to oversized block advancing
this final plat to the governing body.
There have been no public comments
regarding this plat. I stand for
questions.
>> Thank you, Morgan. Uh questions from the
committee.
Questions? Hearing none, we'll open it
up to public comment.
Public comment on this plat
hearing. None. Uh could we have a motion
which includes the exception to block
size?
>> Yes. Uh I move that including the
addition that you just mentioned.
>> Thank you. Is there a second?
>> Second.
>> We have a motion and a second.
Discussion by the committee.
>> Discussion hearing. None. All in favor
signify by saying I.
>> I.
I
>> opposed. The recommendation for Monday
night will be to adopt. With that, we
are con we are done and I appreciate
everybody's time today. Thank you so
much.